{"_id":{"$oid":"591b210d1b491c120cec9fb7"},"id":0,"question":"Arya is a full-time student at a local university. He wants to decide whether he should attend a four-week short semester session, where tuition is IDR 2,000,000, or take a break and work full time at a local exhibition, where he could make as much as IDR 750,000 a week. How much would going to the summer school cost him from a decision-making standpoint? What is the opportunity cost?","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_0","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_0","answer_1":"Total costs\u0009\u0009= IDR 5,000,000 Opportunity cost\u0009= IDR 3,000,000"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b246c1b491c120cec9fb8"},"id":1,"question":"Explain the importance of internal control within organizations. What are the main elements ?","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_1","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_1","answer_1":"The main elements (or components) of internal control are: a.\u0009The control environment. b.\u0009The entity’s risk assessment process. c.\u0009The information system, including the related business processes, relevant to financial reporting, and communication. d.\u0009Control activities. e.\u0009Monitoring of controls."}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b27441b491c120cec9fb9"},"id":2,"question":"UD Maju Tak Gentar (Hary) is engaged in trading of building materials, registered on KPP Jakarta Pulogadung and has been designated as a tax withholder. UD Maju Tak Gentar uses bookkeeping in implementing his tax liability. On 8 January 2013, it paid rental warehouse of Rp60.000.000 to Widodo. How much income tax article 4 (2) should be withheld by UD Maju Tak Gentar on this transaction?","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_2","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_2","answer_1":"Rp 6,000,000."}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b27551b491c120cec9fba"},"id":3,"question":"\r\nAt 31 December 2016, the gross amount of the accounts receivable of PT ABC was IDR100 million. At the same date, there was a related allowance for doubtful debts of IDR 5 million. Revenue from sales is included in the statement of profit or loss and other comprehensive income in the same period as it is included in taxable profit. The tax rate is 25%.\r\nWhat is the amount of deferred tax assets/liabilities to be recognized as at 31 December 2016?\r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_3","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_3","answer_1":"Deferred tax assets of IDR1,250,000"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b27651b491c120cec9fbb"},"id":4,"question":"PT ABC is testing an asset for impairment. The carrying amount of the asset is IDR8.5 billion. The following data has been obtained by PT ABC in relation to the asset:\r\n•\u0009Future cash flows expected to be derived from the asset, IDR10 billion.\r\n•\u0009Estimated fair value of the asset, IDR8 billion.\r\n•\u0009Present value of future cash flows expected to be derived from the asset, IDR6 billion.\r\n•\u0009Costs of disposal for the asset, IDR 200 million.\r\nIn accordance with IAS 36 Impairment of Assets, what is the recoverable amount of the asset?\r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_4","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_4","answer_1":"IDR 7.8 billion."}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b291b1b491c120cec9fbc"},"id":5,"question":"PT ABC is planning to invest in a two-year project that is expected to yield cash flows from operations, net of income taxes, of IDR 500 million in the first year and IDR 800 million in the second year. PT ABC requires an internal rate of return of 15%. The present value of IDR1 for one period at 15% is 0.870 and for two periods at 15% is 0.756. The future value of IDR1 for one period at 15% is 1.150 and for two periods at 15% is 1.323. What is the maximum that PT ABC should invest immediately?","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_5","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_5","answer_1":"IDR 1,030.8 million"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b29db1b491c120cec9fbd"},"id":6,"question":"Some individuals argue that accountants should focus on producing financial statements and leave the design and production of managerial reports to information systems specialists. What are the advantages and disadvantages of following this advice? ","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_6","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_6","answer_1":"There are no advantages to accountants focusing only on financial information. Both the accountant and the organization would suffer if this occurred. Moreover, it would be very costly to have two systems rather than one that captures and processes operational facts at the same time as it captures and reports financial facts. The main disadvantage of this is that accountants would ignore much relevant information about the organization’s activities. "}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b29e91b491c120cec9fbe"},"id":7,"question":"The financial statements of PT AKU SENANG in 2016 shows a profit before tax of Rp500 million. From the financial statements data, it is known that the carrying amount of inventories amounted to Rp250 million however its market value of Rp210 million. Loss on decline in value of inventories has been recognized in the financial statements. Assuming that the 2015 and 2016 sales amount are greater than Rp 50 billion, calculate the amount of corporate income tax expense in 2016?","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_7","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_7","answer_1":"Rp 135 million."}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b32571b491c120cec9fbf"},"id":8,"question":"At 31 December 2015, PT ABC had an item of machinery with a carrying amount of IDR1,400 million (cost IDR2,000 million less accumulated depreciation of IDR600 million). The machinery was purchased on 1 January 2013 and was depreciated at IDR200 million per year based on a useful life of 10 years. On 31 December 2015, it was determined that the recoverable amount of the machinery was IDR1,050 million. Therefore the impairment loss of IDR350 million was recognized.\r\nAfter the depreciation entry for 31 December 2016 had been processed, the recoverable amount of the machinery was reassessed. It was determined that the recoverable amount of the asset at 31 December 2016 was IDR1,280 million.\r\nIn accordance with IAS 16 Property Plant and Equipment and IAS 36 Impairment of Assets, what is the correct entries to recognize the reversal of the impairment loss?\r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":"on","imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_8","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_8","answer_1":""}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b35231b491c120cec9fc0"},"id":9,"question":"A company has issued preference shares that are redeemable at the option of the holder. Three months before the end of the year, it was probable that the holders would require redemption. What is the appropriate classification for the annual payment of IDR12 billion to preference shareholders at the year-end?","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_9","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_9","answer_1":"Interest expense IDR12 billion."}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b352e1b491c120cec9fc1"},"id":10,"question":"During the current fiscal year, Yayasan ABC, a nongovernmental not-for-profit organization, received unrestricted pledges of IDR 3,000 million. Of the pledged amount, IDR 2,000 million was designated by donors for use during the current year, and IDR 1,000 million was designated for next year. Five percent of the pledges are expected to be uncollectible. What amount should Yayasan ABC report as a restricted and non-restricted contributions in the statement of activities for the current year?","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_10","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_10","answer_1":"Unrestricted Contribution: IDR 1,900 million and Temporary Restricted Contibution: IDR 950 million."}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b418b1b491c120cec9fc2"},"id":11,"question":"","qimageCheck":"on","aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_11","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_11","answer_1":"3,200 units"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b41a91b491c120cec9fc3"},"id":12,"question":"An audit trail enables a person to trace a source document to its ultimate effect on the financial statements or work back from amounts in the financial statements to source documents. Describe in detail the audit trail for the sales of inventory?","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_12","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_12","answer_1":"The audit trail for the sale of inventory links the customer order, sales order, and shipping document to the sales invoice. These documents are linked to the journal entry recording the sale of that merchandise. The invoice would also be linked to the cash received from the customer and to the journal entry to record that receipt."}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b41de1b491c120cec9fc4"},"id":13,"question":"During the year to 31 December 2015, you discover that inventories have been overstated by £5,000 (2.5% of profit before tax) and that, in consequence, profits have been overstated by the same amount. During the previous audits you set materiality at 7% of profit before tax. Would you consider that the accounts should be adjusted for the error of £5,000 and why?","qimageCheck":"on","aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_13","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_13","answer_1":"Yes, the adjustment would make profits upward trend will flatten out in the future."}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4ba41b491c120cec9fc5"},"id":14,"question":"For the year ended 31 December 2016, PT ABC had a taxable profit of IDR200 billion. The following comparative information was ascertained from the tax calculations of PT ABC:","qimageCheck":"on","aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_14","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_14","answer_1":"Tax expense: IDR70 billion"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4c411b491c120cec9fc6"},"id":15,"question":"In accordance with IAS 1 Presentation of Financial Statements, what will be the closing retained earnings in the statement of changes in equity for the year ended 31 December 2016?","qimageCheck":"on","aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_15","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_15","answer_1":"IDR29.5 billion"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4c521b491c120cec9fc7"},"id":16,"question":"Foundation ABC received land from a donor who stipulated that the land must remain intact, but any income generated from the property may be used for general activities. In what fund should the Foundation record the donated land?","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_16","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_16","answer_1":"Permanent restricted fund."}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4d6d1b491c120cec9fc8"},"id":17,"question":"\r\nAssume a firm is expected to pay a dividend of IDR 500 per share this year. The firm along with the dividend is expected to grow at a rate of 6%. If the current market price of the stock is IDR 6,000 per share, what is the estimated cost of equity?","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_17","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_17","answer_1":"14.3%"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4d951b491c120cec9fc9"},"id":18,"question":"An outside vendor has just offered to supply the part for CU16 per unit. If the company stops producing this part, one-third of the fixed overhead would be avoided. Should the company make or buy, and what is the difference in the Company net income?","qimageCheck":"on","aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_18","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_18","answer_1":"Make\r\nDifference in net income: CU10,000\r\n"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4dfe1b491c120cec9fca"},"id":19,"question":"What is the profit for the period?","qimageCheck":"on","aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_19","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_19","answer_1":"IDR694,900 thousand"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4e1c1b491c120cec9fcb"},"id":20,"question":"The reporting unit of PT ABC has a fair value of IDR 1,300 million and a carrying value of IDR 1,400 million that includes recorded goodwill of IDR 300 million. The estimated fair value of the identifiable assets minus liabilities is IDR 1,200 million.\r\nCalculate the impairment loss?\r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_20","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_20","answer_1":"IDR 200 million"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4e321b491c120cec9fcc"},"id":21,"question":"PT ABC’s bank requires a compensating balance of 20% on a IDR 100 billion loan. If the stated interest on the loan is 7%, what is the effective cost of the loan?","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_21","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_21","answer_1":"8.75%"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4e571b491c120cec9fcd"},"id":22,"question":"Calculate the end of period liability or asset of defined benefits obligation?","qimageCheck":"on","aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_22","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_22","answer_1":"Liability: IDR 1,843 million"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4e6c1b491c120cec9fce"},"id":23,"question":"During 2016, ABC Lab supplied hospitals with a comprehensive diagnostic kit for CU120. At a volume of 80,000 kits, Thor had fixed costs of CU 1,000,000 and a profit before income taxes of CU 200,000. Due to an adverse legal decision, Thor’s 2017 liability insurance increased by CU 1,200,000 over 2016. Assuming the volume and other costs are unchanged, what should the 2017 price be if ABC is to make the same CU 200,000 profit before income taxes?","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_23","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_23","answer_1":"CU 135 per unit"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4e811b491c120cec9fcf"},"id":24,"question":"Both Achmad and his wife are employees with 3 children, and accumulate their income for income tax purposes. When filing the individual income tax return for year 2016, calculate how much is the non-taxable income allowed as deduction by Achmad?","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_24","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_24","answer_1":"Rp126,000,000"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4e9b1b491c120cec9fd0"},"id":25,"question":"1.\u0009The reporting unit of PT ABC has a fair value of Rp 1,300 million and a carrying book value of Rp 1,400 million that includes recorded goodwill of Rp 300 million. The estimated fair value of the identifiable assets minus liabilities is Rp 1,200 million.\r\nCalculate the impairment loss.\r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_25","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_25","answer_1":"Rp 200 million"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4ea51b491c120cec9fd1"},"id":26,"question":"2.\u0009When an entity prepares separate financial statements, how should it account for investments in subsidiaries, joint ventures and associates?","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_26","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_26","answer_1":"Either at cost, or in accordance with IFRS 9: Financial instruments"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4eb91b491c120cec9fd2"},"id":27,"question":"3.\u0009Summary of underlying economic liability (or asset) and economic expense of the period, with assumed numbers based on the following information retrieved from PT ABC:\r\nPT ABC’s beginning pension obligation is Rp 5,798 million and plan assets are Rp 3,852 million.\r\nReported economic expense of the period: service costs Rp 1,112 million, interest costs Rp 333 million, actuarial gains Rp 59 million, foreign exchange gain Rp 25 million and benefits paid to retired employees of Rp 436 million.\r\nActual return on the plan assets are Rp 241 million\r\nPT ABC contributed Rp 1,223 million to the plan.\r\nCalculate the end of period liability or asset.\r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_27","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_27","answer_1":"Rp 1,843 million - liability"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4ede1b491c120cec9fd3"},"id":28,"question":"4.\u0009Summary of underlying economic liability (or asset) and economic expense of the period, with assumed numbers based on the following information retrieved from PT ABC:\r\nPT ABC’s beginning pension obligation is Rp 5,798 million and plan assets are Rp 3,852 million.\r\nReported economic expense of the period: service costs Rp 1,112 million, interest costs Rp 333 million, actuarial gains Rp 59 million, foreign exchange gain Rp 25 million and benefits paid to retired employees of Rp 436 million.\r\nActual return on the plan assets are Rp 241 million\r\nPT ABC contributed Rp 1,223 million to the plan.\r\nCalculate the net economic expense of the period. \r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_28","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_28","answer_1":"Rp 1,120 million"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4ee81b491c120cec9fd4"},"id":29,"question":"5.\u0009Summary of underlying economic liability (or asset) and economic expense of the period, with assumed numbers based on the following information retrieved from PT ABC:\r\nPT ABC’s beginning pension obligation is Rp 5,798 million and plan assets are Rp 3,852 million.\r\nReported economic expense of the period: service costs Rp 1,112 million, interest costs Rp 333 million, actuarial gains Rp 59 million, foreign exchange gain Rp 25 million and benefits paid to retired employees of Rp 436 million.\r\nActual return on the plan assets are Rp 241 million\r\nPT ABC contributed Rp 1,223 million to the plan.\r\nCalculate the ending balance of the plan assets.\r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_29","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_29","answer_1":"Rp 4,880 million"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4ef11b491c120cec9fd5"},"id":30,"question":"6.\u0009Summary of underlying economic liability (or asset) and economic expense of the period, with assumed numbers based on the following information retrieved from PT ABC:\r\nPT ABC’s beginning pension obligation is Rp 5,798 million and plan assets are Rp 3,852 million.\r\nReported economic expense of the period: service costs Rp 1,112 million, interest costs Rp 333 million, actuarial gains Rp 59 million, foreign exchange gain Rp 25 million and benefits paid to retired employees of Rp 436 million.\r\nActual return on the plan assets are Rp 241 million\r\nPT ABC contributed Rp 1,223 million to the plan.\r\nCalculate the ending balance of the pension obligation.\r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_30","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_30","answer_1":"Rp 6,723 million"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4ef91b491c120cec9fd6"},"id":31,"question":"7.\u0009Summary of underlying economic liability (or asset) and economic expense of the period, with assumed numbers based on the following information retrieved from PT ABC:\r\nPT ABC’s beginning pension obligation is Rp 5,798 million and plan assets are Rp 3,852 million.\r\nReported economic expense of the period: service costs Rp 1,112 million, interest costs Rp 333 million, actuarial gains Rp 59 million, foreign exchange gain Rp 25 million and benefits paid to retired employees of Rp 436 million.\r\nActual return on the plan assets are Rp 241 million\r\nPT ABC contributed Rp 1,223 million to the plan.\r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_31","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_31","answer_1":"Rp 1,946 million"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4f851b491c120cec9fd7"},"id":32,"question":"","qimageCheck":"on","aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_32","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_32","answer_1":"Closing retained earnings - $ 295,000."}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b4fdb1b491c120cec9fd8"},"id":33,"question":"What is the amount of cash collected from customers during the year ended 30 June 20X6?","qimageCheck":"on","aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_33","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_33","answer_1":"$ 412,500."}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b50291b491c120cec9fd9"},"id":34,"question":"10.\u0009ABC Ltd. reports quarterly and has an operating loss carry forward of $10,000 for income tax purposes at the start of the current financial year for which a deferred tax asset has not been recognised. The entity earns $10,000 in the first quarter of the current year and expects to earn $10,000 in each of the three remaining quarters. Excluding the carryforward, the estimated average annual income tax rate is expected to be 40 per cent. Actual earnings match expectations.\r\nHow much is the tax expense to be recognized in the first quarter?\r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_34","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_34","answer_1":"CU 3,000"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b50321b491c120cec9fda"},"id":35,"question":"11.\u0009For the year ended 30 June 20X7, ABC Ltd had an accounting profit of $200,000 and a taxable profit of $170,000. The tax expense of ABC Ltd for the year ended 30 June 20X7 was $60,000. At 30 June 20X7, it was determined that the company had a deferred tax liability of $27,000. Assume that there was no deferred tax asset at the beginning or end of the period. What is the deferred tax liability as at 30 June 20X6?\r\nThe tax rate is 30 per cent.\r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_35","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_35","answer_1":"The deferred tax liability as at 30 June 20X6 was $18,000."}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b503b1b491c120cec9fdb"},"id":36,"question":"12.\u0009A company reports and recognizes the following in relation to its receivables:\r\nGross amount receivable\u0009\u0009$80m\r\nProvision for doubtful debts\u0009   $6m\r\nWhat is the maximum credit risk that it must disclose in the notes in accordance with IFRS?\r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_36","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_36","answer_1":"None."}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b50661b491c120cec9fdc"},"id":37,"question":"","qimageCheck":"on","aimageCheck":"on","imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_37","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_37","answer_1":""}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b50741b491c120cec9fdd"},"id":38,"question":"\r\n14.\u0009ABC Ltd. reporting quarterly expects to earn CU 10,000 pre-tax each quarter and operates in a jurisdiction with a tax rate of 20% on the first CU 20,000 of annual earnings and 30% on all additional earnings. Actual earnings match expectations.\r\nWhat is the amount of interim income tax expense to be reported in the second quarter?\r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_38","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_38","answer_1":"CU 2,500"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b508d1b491c120cec9fde"},"id":39,"question":"","qimageCheck":"on","aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_39","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_39","answer_1":"Residual income: Division A= CU200; Division B= CU250\r\nDivision B is more successful\r\n"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b509b1b491c120cec9fdf"},"id":40,"question":"\r\n16.\u0009PT. Sarana Mandiri is considering employing a sales manager. Market research has shown that a good sales manager can increase the profit by 30 %, an average one by 20% and a poor one by 10 %. Experience has shown that the company has attracted a good sales manager 35 % of the time, an average one 45 % of the time and a poor one 20 % of the time. The company’s normal profits are IDR 1.8 billion per annum and the sales manager’s salary would be IDR 400 million per annum.\r\n\r\nBased on the expected value criterion, what is the correct advice that PT. Sarana Mandiri should be given ?\r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_40","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_40","answer_1":"Therefore do not employ sales manager as profit will fall by IDR 13 million "}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b50a71b491c120cec9fe0"},"id":41,"question":"17.\u0009What is the difference between authentication and authorization?","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_41","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_41","answer_1":"Authentication and authorization are two related controls designed to restrict access to an organization’s information systems and resources.\r\nThe objective of authentication is to verify the claimed identity of someone attempting to obtain access.\r\nThe objective of authorization is to limit what an authenticated user can do once they have been given access. \r\n"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b50b41b491c120cec9fe1"},"id":42,"question":"18.\u0009PT Prima Makmur is planning to buy an asset in the next accounting period at an estimated cost of IDR 100 billion but it is concerned that the cost of buying the asset will rise. PT Prima Makmur can designate the risk of the future payment rising as a hedge item and enter into derivative, the hedging instrument to cover the risk. What type of hedge accounting based on this case? ","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_42","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_42","answer_1":"Cash flow hedge "}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b50bd1b491c120cec9fe2"},"id":43,"question":"20.\u0009A division is considering investing in capital equipment costing IDR 2.7 billion. \r\nThe useful economic life of the equipment is expected to be 50 years, with no resale value at the end of the period. The forecast return on the initial investment is 15 % per annum before depreciation. The division’s cost of capital is 7 %.\r\nWhat is the expected annual residual income of the intial investment ? \r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_43","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_43","answer_1":"IDR 162 million "}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b50c81b491c120cec9fe3"},"id":44,"question":"21.\u0009An impairment loss is recognised to the extent the carrying amount of the asset exceeds its recoverable amount. For assets carried at historical cost, impairment losses  are recognised as __________","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_44","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_44","answer_1":"-\u0009an expense immediately in profit or loss."}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b50d21b491c120cec9fe4"},"id":45,"question":"22.\u0009In order to ensure the policies of an organisation are consistent with the public interest, the directors of company should focus on the collective well-being of __________","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_45","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_45","answer_1":"stakeholders"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b50d91b491c120cec9fe5"},"id":46,"question":"23.\u0009Professional accountants must demonstrate __________ at all times by applying consistently high moral values. ","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_46","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_46","answer_1":"Integrity"}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b50e21b491c120cec9fe6"},"id":47,"question":"24.\u0009The major purpose of the International Accounting Standards Board (IASB) is to ensure consitency in __________ __________\r\nWhat are two words complete the sentence above ? \r\n","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_47","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_47","answer_1":"corporate reporting "}
{"_id":{"$oid":"591b50ea1b491c120cec9fe7"},"id":48,"question":"25.\u0009Classifying commission earned as revenue in the statement of profit or loss, having previously classified it as other operating income. This activity is a change of accounting policy under IAS  __________","qimageCheck":null,"aimageCheck":null,"imageQues":"../images/uploaded_images/ques_48","imageAns":"../images/uploaded_images/ans_48","answer_1":"IAS 8: Accounting Policies, Changes in Accounting Estimates and Errors."}
